Contact

rodrigocruz@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rodrigocruz-ml (LinkedIn) github.com/rodrigocruz13 (Portfolio)

Top Skills

C (Programming Language)
Business Process Improvement
Machine Learning

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Publications

C static libraries

Libraries. Dynamic & Static
Links on Unix
IOT - Internet of things
What happens when you type "ls -l"
in the shell ?, mmmm

Rodrigo Cruz Ayala.

+57 3127948317 rodrigocruz@outlook.com, rodrigocruzayala@gmail.com

Machine learning student at Holberton School. Software developer Industrial Engineer

Summary

Fullstack developer with strengths in C language and Shell scripting and high level languages (Python); Machine Learning: supervised and unsupervised learning and also frameworks like Numpy, Tensorflow, Keras and Matplotlib.

Extensive experience Customer Success (CS), process optimization, logistics, quality systems (QS) and human resources (HS). Talented at identifying problems, suggesting and designing recommendations and leading deployments of improvements and solutions, increasing the performance of any organization.

Strong analytical skills, initiative, quality service, getting things done, and leading groups and teams with a high sense of respect for others as human beings

Experience

Bunny Studio
Algorithm Engineer
November 2019 - January 2020 (3 months)
Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Design and present proposals to improve the current software implementation.

Holberton School Apprenticeship - Full Stack Software engineering January 2019 - November 2019 (11 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

Holberton school is a peer-learning, project-guided, full stack software engineering school in San Francisco.

Projects:

- Printf project: creation in C language of an enhancement version of the printf function included in the C standard library.

- Simple Shell project: creation of a simple version of the shell that comes by default in Linux systems (bash). Made with C language (syscalls, standard I/O, child processes, signals and interrupts).
- Monty Interpreter project: creation of an interpreter to use stacks and queues (LIFO and FIFO).
- Sorting Algorithms: implementation of the most famous sorting algorithms and computation of the Big O notation.
- AirBnB-clone: creation of a clone of the AirBnB web application recognized for vacation rentals.
- Storage Engine for Web Applications (made on Python)
- Database Storage Engine for Web Applications (made on Python, SQL and Sqlalchemy as ORM)
- Design of web deployment, web server with Nginx, load balancer with HAproxy with round-robin algorithm and deployment with puppet.

UNIMINUTO Colombia

Planning Engineer

January 2017 - January 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

UNIMINUTO. (Rectoría Calle 80 - 'Main Branch' - Colombia)

Planning Engineer 2017 - 2018

- Creating automated tools to verify data structure and consistency between all four databases (SII, Banner, Program master plan)
- Auditing data processing and generating failure reports.
- Assisting all departments to extract relevant information from its metrics

UNIMINUTO Sede Cundinamarca Quality System head & Customer Service head June 2013 - 2016 (3 years)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Maintaining the Quality System (QS) by the ISO 9001: v.2008 standards
- Creation of a permanent metric monitoring system for the QS.
- Maintaining the lowest complaint score of 20.000 students.
- Creator of the Complaints and claims control system
- Establishing the foundations of data analysis at the Cundinamarca branch.
- Auditing all areas according to the annual plan
- Training for over 500 employees in Quality Systems topics and Customer Service at over 30 locations.
- Delivering solutions for the complaints in the specified frame of time

- Creating and leading a multi-person logistic project for the beginning of each academic semester

IGA Consultores S.A.S.

Logistics Chief, Planning head & Human Resources Consultant January 2008 - September 2012 (4 years 9 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Create and deploy the logistics process for the outplacement activities in 22 cities.
- Creation of tools to generate human maps according to the required quantities established by the clients
- Create and monitoring statistical reports
- Design custom metrics for clients to implement a Document management system (DMS)
- Creation of databases of the company
- Coordinate the reception, inspection, and readiness of products and supplies

UNIMINUTO Sede Cundinamarca

Math, Statistics and Tech - Tutor January 2010 - May 2012 (2 years 5 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- [Courses] Intro to tech. Statistics. Algebra. Differential calculus. Integral calculus.
- Assist students with any difficulty during the learning process.
- Find and implement better teaching strategies to increase the learning rate.

TELECONSULTORES S.A.

Internal Control Coordinator

April 2007 - December 2007 (9 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Creation, follow up, and monitoring daily warehouse and workers inventory.
- Conduct administrative and inventory software implementation inside the company

DH Soluciones Informáticas S.A.S (DHS)

Technical Sales Consultant

April 2006 - December 2006 (9 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Collection of prospects requirements.
- Company's introduction and product demonstration.
- Generate documentation for invoicing and dispatch.

Page 3 of 5

- Control of collection from all customers.
- Generate weekly performance reports.

DI PIÙ S.A.

Logistics Chief.

January 2006 - March 2006 (3 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Evaluation and selection of suppliers.
- Coordinate reception, inspection, and stock of products and supplies.
- Planning and dispatch of supplies and products to the stores.
- Enforce guarantees for defective products.
- Management of transfers, returns, loans and guarantees

Linalca Informatica SA

Quality System Coordinator and Logistics Assistant.

April 2005 - December 2005 (9 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Design the structure and coordinate the maintenance and improvement of the Document Management System (DMS)
- Provide support to all areas related to Quality and Standardization issues.
- Conduct training to all personnel and raise awareness of the company's Quality System (QS).
- Generate reports on logistics and quality area indicators.
- Design and implement the company's document and records structure
- Assist in the areas designated by Logistics Management and General Management

Velto S.A.

Internal Control Coordinator

June 2004 - December 2004 (7 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Monitor daily warehouse and inventory movements.
- Investigate, follow up, solve problems presented in the QS to obtain ISO 9001 v:2000 certificate.
- Provide support to the Sales Department by creating and implementing the CRM system.
- Provide support to the Production Department by reporting issues (product quality, and plant physical incidents).
- Assist in designated tasks ordered by General Manager.

Devinil S.A.

Quality and Standards Assistant.

March 2003 - November 2003 (9 months)

Bogota, D.C., Capital District, Colombia

- Maintaining and improving the Quality System metrics.
- Organize meetings to generate improvement proposals for the organization.
- Develop and deploy improvement plans for the production area.
- Assist in the appropriate tasks of Quality Department

Education

Holberton School

Machine learning deepening (2020 - 2021)

Holberton School

Software engineer, Computer Software Engineering · (2019 - 2019)

Tompkins Cortland Community College

Advance english · (2015 - 2015)

Escuela Colombiana de Ingeniería 'Julio Garavito' Industrial Engineer, Business Administration, Management and Operations · (1996 - 2002)

Universidad de Los Andes

Computers and Comunications Engineering · (1993 - 1995)